A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office Files of Mary Loftus FA1428
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Office Files of Mary Loftus
1974-2005
1995-1999
Rockefeller Archive Center
Loftus, Mary
Ford Foundation
FA1428
2.85 Cubic Feet 8 boxes (7 document containers, 1 half document container)
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed of files from the Ford Foundation's Office of Communications, including correspondence, annual report draft files, draft files for other Ford Foundation reports, and files related to the creation of the Ford Foundation's early website. The bulk of the material in the collection spans from 1995-1999.
Arrangement
Arranged in the order received from the Ford Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Mary Loftus served as the Manager of Information Dissemination and Administration in the Office of Communications at the Ford Foundation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2017 and 2019 by the Ford Foundation and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2017:087, 2019:151, and 2019:178.
Communications; Ford Foundation
- Ford Foundation Letter - Index, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Contract with University Microfilms International (re Letter and Copyright for Letter), 1975 April-2000 November (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Internet/Web Site Background, 1995 December-1997 October (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Ford Foundation Website Log Information: Publication Requests, 1997 February-2004 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ford Foundation Web Site Flap File, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Web Site Permissions File, 1996 October-1998 August (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Ford Foundation Website - Bills, 1998 June-2000 January (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Website Contracts, Etc., 1998 April-December (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Equipment File - Purchase Orders, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mary Loftus Correspondence, 1999 June-September (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Mary Loftus Correspondence, 1999 October-December (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1999 January-March (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1998 October-December (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1998 July-September (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Mary Loftus Chron File, 1999 April-June (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Office of Communications Purchase Order Logs, 1998 September-1999 October (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Annual Report 1999, 1998 September-2000 May (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence, quotes from printers, printing specifications, general mailing list
- Job #97-13A 1997 Annual Report - General, 1997 December-1998 November (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
- Job #97-13C 1997 Annual Report - Officers/Trustees/Directors, 1997 March-1998 June (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
- Job #97-12E 1997 Annual Report - Representatives, 1998 March-July (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Job #97-13H 1997 Annual Report - Poll File, 1998 February-June (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Ford Foundation in Listings and Directories, 1989-2005 (Box 3, Folder 25-28)
- Job #98-01 Ford Foundation Spring/Summer Report - General, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Job #98-02 1998 Fall Report - General (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Job #98-04 Catalog of Publications, Films and Videos, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Job #98-06 Current Interests - General, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Job #98-08 President's Message Annual Report 1997, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Job #98-09 Press Release: Ford Foundation Grant of $50 Million Will Generate $2 Billion in Affordable Mortgages (Fannie Mae), 1998 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Job #98-10 Lessons from London, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Job #98-12 Innovations 1998 - General File (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Job #98-12 Ford Foundation Appoints South African Writer Educator as Resident Scholar, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Job #98-14 Press Release: Ford Foundation Grants $5.3 Million For Devolution Initiative, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 38)
- Job #99-01 1998 Annual Report - General, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Job #99-01 1998 Annual Report - Letters to Congress, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 40)
- Job #99-02 1999 Winter Report - General (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Job #99-03 Spring/Summer Report - General, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Job #99-04 Press Release: Richard Moe Joins Board of Trustees, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 43)
- Job #99-05 Fall 1999 Report (Box 5, Folder 44)
- Job #99-06 Press Release: Ford and Mott Create National Program to Improve Race and Ethnic Programs, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Job #99-07 Presidents Message 1998, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Statement of Investments, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Job #99-08 Reprint: American Philanthropic Values, Berresford Speech, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Job #99-09 Global Law Practices Learning Initiative, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Job #99-10 Innovations 1999, 1998-1999 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Job #99-11 Press Release: VP Texaco Joins Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Ford Foundation Reports Catalog Project, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 52)
- Report, Winter 1999, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 53)
- Printing Correspondence, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 54)
- Trustee At-a-Glance Booklet, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 55)
- Press Release: Ford Foundation Appoints New Vice President for Communications, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Press Release: President and CEO of Alcoa Joins Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Press Release: Paul A. Allaire to Succeed Henry B. Schacht as Chairman of Ford Foundation Board of Trustees, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Press Release: Ford Foundation Grants $2 Million to Major Journalism Magazines, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Job #00-10 Current Interests, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 60)
- Job #00-12 Ford Foundation Good Neighbor Committee, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 61)
- Job #00-14 Press Release: Ford Foundation Launches Award Program, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 62)
- Job #00-15 Innovations, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 63)
- Job #00-13 Collaborations that Count, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 64)
- Job #00-17 Arts Initiative Campaign, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 65)
- Annual Report Research, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Standing Annual Report File, 1993-1998 (Box 6, Folder 67)
- Older Annual Reports - Miscellaneous Information, 1996-1998 (Box 6, Folder 68)
- Wilmer Shields Rich Awards Program, Council on Foundations, 1993-2002 (Box 6, Folder 69-70)
- Council on Foundations (Update), 1990-1998 (Box 7, Folder 71)
- Wilmer Shields Rich Awards Certificates, 1995-1998 (Box 7, Folder 72)
- Publisher's Trade List Annual (R. R. Bowker), 1984-1996 (Box 7, Folder 73)
- ISSN, 1976-1995 (Box 7, Folder 74)
- Bowker (General), 1995-2001 (Box 7, Folder 75)
- Advance Book Information/Books in Print (Bowker), 1982-1997 (Box 7, Folder 76)
- ISBN - Bowker, 1989-2000 (Box 7, Folder 77)
- Library of Congress - Correspondence (Cataloging in Publication Data), 1974-1999 (Box 7, Folder 78)
- Bulk Requests, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 79)
- Acknowledgments, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 80)